Blake Condrey

Full Stack Software Engineer

<u>▶E-Mail</u> <u>▶Portfolio Website</u> <u>▶LinkedIn</u> <u>▶GitHub</u> **▶Active** TS/SCI

SUMMARY OF QUALIFICATIONS

Results-focused, growth-oriented Software Engineer with a demonstrated distinction in the Defense and Space Industry. Seeking to become an immediate asset to software solutions teams deploying innovative products for customers through implementation of proven skills in full stack development, coupled with effective communication, adaptability, and creative problem-solving skills realized from 6+ years of servant leadership experience in the sales and Defense industries.

TECHNICAL SKILLS/PROJECTS

Languages/Tools:

Python | JavaScript | C++ | Java | HTML5/CSS3/Bootstrap | Flask Python | SQL | Linux Apache

Sorting Visualization Tool

- Web App that generates an array of columns, and visualizes the bubble sort, insertion sort, selection sort, merge sort, and quick sort algorithms.
- Built with ES6, Node.js, Responsive Web Design Technologies, deployed on Heroku.

Python-Flask News Aggregator

- Flask Web App which utilizes the newsapi-python REST API to curate an aggregated news page.
- Built with Flask Framework implementing SQLAlchemy and Web Forms, UI/UX Tools, and Linux Apache

EDUCATION

Microsoft Systems and Software Academy

Oct. 2021 – Feb. 2022

Cloud Applications Development Participant

- 17-week Cloud Applications Development course deploying web/console-based applications by utilizing:

- C# - ASP.NET Core MVC - T-SQL - Azure - Visual Studio

Southern New Hampshire University, GPA 3.9

Expected Graduation May 2023

B.S. Computer Science – Software Engineering

Distance Learning/Manchester, NH

Relevant Courses:

- Computer Programming Languages (C++) Foundations in Application Development (Java)
- Quantitative Analysis Data Structures and Algorithms (C++) Physics Calculus

WORK EXPERIENCE

United States Air Force

Jan. 2018 – Present

Command Post, Shift Supervisor

Colorado Springs, CO

- Communicated daily to senior Pentagon directors via tailored reports with real-time command and control data and situational awareness which enabled the direction of time-critical decisions to sixteen units operating \$22.6B in space satellites and ground radars with no mission or product losses.
- Developed emergency management and disaster preparedness program across four installations, five Air Force
 organizations, and over 30 geographically separated units, that continually safeguards 25,000 personnel and \$5B in
 Department of Defense assets.
- Deciphered 230 emergency time-sensitive messages to direct base defense augmentation, alert base directors of sabotage or acts of war, and report to defense headquarters of completed postures at a 100% success rate within four measured components of a two-minute window, protecting 440,000 civilians and 25,000 DoD members.

Verizon Wireless Jul. 2015 – Jul. 2017

Solutions Specialist

Chattanooga, TN

- Engaged with walk-in customers to discover needs and expose shortfalls, producing game changing solutions that resulted in 168% year-over-year increased sales revenue.
- Developed product bundles by leveraging existing quantity discounts to provide customers with the best wireless solutions, exceeding sales targets by 130% for 18 consecutive months.